Kendra Kwoka

Austin, Texas, 78727 Phone: 936.520.3642

Email: kendrakwoka@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://ancient-castle-12194.herokuapp.com/

Github: https://github.com/kkwoka

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kendra-kwoka-553b68196/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with experience building responsive and progressive web applications for today's market. A passionate, hard-worker and lifelong learner, always expanding knowledge and skills with the latest trends and technologies available. Experienced team player equipped with the technical know-how and personal drive necessary to get every job done efficiently and precisely. Equipped with skills needed to create products that enrich the lives of users.

Technical Skills

Deployment: Heroku, Git

Databases: MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB,

IndexedDB

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Popper.js / Tippy.js, Local Storage, Session

Storage, APIs, VUE.js, Material-ui

Server-Side Development: User

Authentication, Sequelize, Mongoose, MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)

Quality and Performance: Unit Testing, Google Lighthouse, Webpack, PWAs (Progressive Web

Apps), Lazy Loading, Service Workers

Education

Bootcamp Certificate (Full Stack): Trilogy Education Services / University of Texas - Austin // Grade: A+

A 24-week, Full Stack, intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Science in Speech Language Pathology: University of Texas - Austin // GPA: 3.74

Communication Science and Disorders - academic preparation in the normal processes of communication and its development, as well as in the identification and treatment of communication disorders.

Projects

A La Board

https://github.com/kkwoka/A_La_Board | https://warm-bayou-44198.herokuapp.com/

- An app for board game enthusiasts to find new games that interest them and save them to their account. Users can then narrow down their saved board games by multiple options (ex: player size, max play time) to pick the perfect board game to play with any party group.
- My Core Responsibilities:
 - o MySQL GET requests from database && POST requests to database
 - o Created all pages except 'hotitems' page
 - o All page layouts (except hotitems) and UI styling / polishing via Material-ui.
 - o Tools / Languages: MySQL / JawsDB, React.js, JavaScript, Material-ui, Boardgamegeek API

https://github.com/kkwoka/C-19 | https://secret-spire-45995.herokuapp.com/

- A COVID-19 patient portal, easily accessed by physicians nationwide, for storing patient information to ensure accurate tracking and reporting of tested patients.
- My Core Responsibilities:
 - o Set up local and heroku databases for patient information storage.
 - o Created 'Add' and 'Delete' database manipulation routes
 - o Created all page url routings
- Tools / Languages: MySQL / JawsDB, Vue.js, JavaScript

Smorgas-Chord

https://github.com/kkwoka/Smorgas-Chord | https://kkwoka.github.io/Smorgas-Chord/

- Allows the user to search lyrics and guitar tabs for popular songs using two different API. The
 lyrics will appear on the page while the guitar tabs will open into a separate Songsterr page.
 The previously searched songs will appear in the history as clickable links, should the user
 want to look through their search history and pull up song and lyric information from
 previous searches.
- My Core Responsibilities:
 - o All JavaScript code: Connecting to & displaying both Lyrics and Tabs API based on user input, user input's history storage
- Tools / Languages: JavaScript / jQuery, APIs (Happi.dev, Songsterr, Kanye.rest), AJAX, Bulma CSS, Tippy.js

Work History

Bouldin Creek Cafe, Austin, Texas — Server

(November 2019 - Current)

Served customers at busy restaurant. Waited 6-12 tables (18-70 people) at any given time. Responsible for ensuring great customer experience while meticulously caring for individual allergies / medical conditions / dietary restrictions. Required meticulous eye for detail and gathering information.

${\bf Ludington\ Bay\ Brewing\ Co.,\ Ludington,\ Michigan-\it Bartender/Server}$

(April 2019 - October 2019)

Tended bar with 1-100 occupants at a time. Learned about brewing and canning processes of beer. Hosted, tended bar, and served for events in the 'landing room' with 10-30 people. Required consistent and positive team work in high-traffic and hectic times.

*** Took time off to travel around America with my dog! ***

REI, Austin, Texas—Sales Lead, SIF

(July 2016 - November 2018)

Due to strong leadership and interpersonal communication skills, worked closely with Store Management, Visual Lead, and Sales Leads to identify, research, and resolve customer and employee issues. By performing unique transactions: special orders, class registration, special ticket sales, store mail-outs, customer service skills significantly sharpened.

Peached Tortilla, Austin, Texas — Asst. Operations Mngr; Warehouse Mngr; Food Truck Mngr; Shift Lead

(August 2015 - July 2016)

Showcased my attention to detail, decision making, and organizational skills by creating a new scheduling system which resolved previous scheduling issues. Organizational, time management, and leadership skills significantly strengthened by working concurrently as Shift Lead, Food Truck Manager, Warehouse Manager, and Asst. Operations Manager.

Austin Java (Barton Springs), Austin, Texas — Team Lead; Bartender/Server

(November 2014 - July 2015)

Gained significant experience in working under pressure. Team management skills: Supervised team of 5–15 individuals. Assisted management to resolve customer / employee / scheduling issues, food / alcohol orders. Helped with management, front-of-house and back-of-house duties. Supervised/worked special events in a rentable meeting room.